RG 030, Council of Defense
Connecticut State Library
- Series 1. General
  - 1. Classified file, 1917-1919
    - K. Manpower and Labor (Box 45)
      - K388.9: Mr. Herbert Knox Smith’s Correspondence (Box 50)
      - K388.9: Strikes (Box 50)
      - K389: Industrial Mediation and Arbitration (Box 50)
      - K902: [Pamphlet: “Organization of the Committee, Scope and Objects..” (Council of National Defense)] (Box 50)
    - L. Military and Naval (Box 50)
      - L: Military and Naval - Recruiting and Enrollment in Army and Navy (Box 50)
      - L: Clippings (Box 50)
      - L: Military and Naval Committee - Correspondence of Admiral Cowles and Col.Cowles (Box 50)
      - L14: Recruiting & Enlistment (Box 51)
      - L14: Applications for Enlistment (Box 51)
      - L14.2: British Recruiting Mission (Box 51)
      - L15: Draft (Box 51)
      - L15: [Report Provost Marshall General to Secretary of Defense: “On the First Draft under the Selective Service act 1917”] (Box 51)
      - L16: Registration (Box 51)
      - L16.1: Registration Day, 1917 June 5 (Box 51)
      - L16.2: Registration Day, 1918 June 5 (Box 51)
      - L16.3: Registration, 1918 September 12 (Box 51)
      - L17: Exemptions (Box 51)
      - L17.01: Herbert Knox Smith’s Correspondence re Draft Exemptions (Box 51)
      - L17.02: Occupational Exemptions - Classification of Employees H.K. Smith’s and F.D. Cheney’s Industrial Survey (Box 51)
      - L17.03: Industrial advices to District Draft Boards] (Box 51)
      - L17.1: Boards (Box 51)
      - L17.1: Lists of Draft Boards, etc. (Box 51)
      - L17.2: Classification of Connecticut towns by exemption Districts (Box 51)
      - L17.3: Crowder, E. H. - Rulings re Exemptions and Instructions For Local Boards, etc. (Box 52)
      - L17.31: Governor’s Circulars to Local Boards, Medical, etc. also Major Buckley’s Letters (Box 52)
      - L17.32: Governor’s Medical Aide (Dr. D. Chester Brown) - Circulars (Box 53)
      - L17.33: Circulars to Local Boards by Connecticut Council of Defense (Box 53)
      - L17.34: Local Board Progress charts (Box 53)
      - L17.4: Exempted Aliens (Box 53)
      - L17.5: Exemption of Harvey Levine (Box 53)
      - L17.6: Aid for Local Draft Boards (Box 53)
      - L17.7: [Letter - Physical Defects as Found by Exemption Boards] (Box 53)
      - L17.8: Boards of Instructions - Meetings of Drafted Men (Box 53)
      - L17.9: Agricultural Registrants (Box 53)
      - L18: Population (Box 53)
      - L19: Need of speeding up Military Plans (Box 53)
      - L20: Lists of Names on Honor Rolls in Towns (Box 53)
      - L20: List of Connecticut Men in the Service (Letters we sent re Lists and Cards) (Box 53)
      - L20: Honor Rolls (General Material re) (Box 53)
      - L20: Regular Army Enlistments (Box 53)
      - L20: Lists of Men in Service - Compiled from Records at Washington - Sent to us by B.F. English, 2 folders (Box 53)
      - L20.02: Proper Recognition on Honor Rolls for those who have died, been wounded, been Decorated in Service (Box 54)
      - L20.03: Honor Rolls - What Names Should Appear - Pictures of Honor Rolls (Box 54)
      - L21: [One Year Extra Pay Plan - Payment of Soldiers] (Box 54)
      - L21.2: [Massachusetts law - An Act to Provide State Pay for Soldiers and Sailors] (Box 54)
      - L23.33: [Soldier’s Business Aid Committee - North Carolina] (Box 54)
      - L25: Regimental and Company Funds (Box 54)
      - L29: Crowder, E.H. - Rulings re Movement of Men (Box 54)
      - L30: Military Training (Box 54)
      - L31: Training Camps - Lists, etc. - Officers Camps (Box 54)
      - L32: Training Camps - Recreation and Activities (Box 54)
      - L33: War Camp Recreation Fund (Box 54)
      - L34: Students Army Training Corps (Box 54)
      - L34.01: List of High School Graduates - Letter re Student Army Training Corps (Box 54)
      - L35: Military training in Secondary Schools (Box 54)
      - -----: [Wagon Companies] (Box 55)
      - -----: [Newspaper: NY Times 9/1/1918: Who’s Who in our Army on West Front] (Box 55)
      - L101: List of Commanding Officers. (Box 55)
      - L101: Fort Sheridan Association Letters (Box 55)
      - L102: Death of Soldier’s (Box 55)
      - L103: [Danger to Released or Discharged soldiers] (Box 55)
      - L151: [Machine Gun Formation] (Box 55)
      - L229.9: Peach Stones, Fruit Pits, etc. Needed for Manufacture of Gas Masks (Box 55)
      - L230: Saw Mill Units (Box 55)
      - L300: [Pamphlets on US Navy Recruiting and Naval Invention] (Box 55)
      - L301: [Navy and Marine Corps List and Directory] (Box 55)
      - L302: Chronometers (Box 55)
      - L325: Merchant Marine (Box 55)
      - L325.07: Training Men for Merchant Marine Service (Box 55)
      - L455: [Pamphlet on Naval Coast Defense Reserve and Volunteer Naval Reserve, and Enrollment in Naval Reserve] (Box 55)
      - L500: Letter re Invention of Device to Destroy Submarines (Box 55)
      - L501: Binoculars, spyglasses & telescopes, etc. (Box 55)
      - L505: Aviation (Box 55)
      - L600: [Press Release re Agricultural Students] (Box 55)
    - M. State Protection (Box 55)
      - M12: Connecticut Home Guard - Circulars, General Orders, etc. (Box 55)
      - M12: Home guard (Box 55)
      - M15: Bulletin - “Are You Helping The Kaiser?” (Box 55)
      - M18: Disloyalty (Box 55)
      - M19: Men to Serve for Navy Dept.. for Investigating Suspicious Cases (Box 56)
      - M20: Individual cases of Suspected Disloyalty (Box 56)
      - M23: Spies. Espionage (Box 56)
      - M24: Pro-German Books, Literature to be Suppressed (Box 56)
      - M24: German Propaganda (Box 56)
      - M24.01: Hearst publication (Box 56)
      - M24.02: [Pamphlet: “Stop Malicious Rumors - Help Win The War”] (Box 56)
      - M24.03: [Fake Hoover Letter] (Box 56)
      - M25: [Protection For Industrial Plants] (Box 56)
      - M26: [Guarding Reservoirs] (Box 56)
      - M27: Protection of bridges (Box 56)
      - M28: Alien Property (Box 56)
      - M50: Registration of Aliens (Box 56)
      - M54: Deportation of Aliens (Box 56)
      - M60: Desertion - General Correspondence, Circular Letters (Box 56)
      - M60: Collective Reports, Bi-Weekly, etc. of Desertions (Arranged by date) (Box 56)
      - M60: Desertions - Press Notices (Box 56)
      - M60: Deserters - Detection and Apprehension - Draft Evaders (Box 57)
      - M70: [Volunteer Home Defense Police] (Box 57)
      - M921.03: [Massachusetts Legislation re Defense of the Commonwealth] (Box 57)
    - N. Transportation See Transportation File, Boxes 329-335 (Box 57)
    - P. Sanitation and Medicine (Box 57)
      - P01: Committee on Sanitation and Medicine (Box 57)
      - P12: Health (Box 57)
      - P12.01: Texas Health Survey (Box 57)
      - P25.32: NY, State - Enforcement of Quarantine Laws (Box 57)
      - P26: Health and Recreation Bureau (Box 57)
      - P26.06: Health & Recreation Conferences, 1918 January 25 (Box 57)
      - P26.061: [Travelers’ Aid Conference] (Box 57)
      - P27: Police Women (Box 57)
      - P27: [Police Women For Norwich] (Box 57)
      - P28: Venereal Diseases, Sex Education, etc. (Box 57)
      - P28.01: Connecticut State Farm For Women, East Lyme, Connecticut (Box 58)
      - P30: Moral Conditions of Training Camps (Box 58)
      - P31: Committee on the Protection of Girls (Box 58)
      - P99: Physicians (Box 58)
      - P99: Volunteer Medical Service Corps (Box 58)
      - P100: [Medical Officers Reserve Corps] (Box 58)
      - P102: Medical and Surgical Census (Box 58)
      - P103: [List of Physicians Subject to Emergency Calls of Manufacturers] (Box 58)
      - P105: Owen Bill (Box 58)
      - P110: Hospitals - Hospital Interns (Box 58)
      - P110.01: Insanity (Box 58)
      - P110.60: Canadian Military Hospitals Commission (Box 58)
      - P111: Nurses - Press Notices (Box 58)
      - P111: Pupil Nurses - (Correspondence with County Chairmen), 1917 (Box 58)
      - -----: Press re Nurses (Box 58)
      - -----: Nurses - List of Applicants (Box 58)
      - P111: Nurses - Hospitals, Requests for Lists, Names, Applicants (Box 58)
      - P111: Nurses (Box 58)
      - P111.1: Nurses For Spanish Influenza Epidemic (Box 58)
      - P115: [Report on Tuberculosis] (Box 58)
      - P116: Spanish influenza (Box 58)
      - P116.01: [Poster: “To Parent Influenza”] (Box 58)
      - P125: Dentists (Box 58)
    - Q. Committee on Americanization (Box 59)
      - Q: Press Items re Americanization Department (Box 59)
      - Q01: Americanization Department - Organization, etc. (Box 59)
      - Q01: Lists of Americanization Committees (Box 59)
      - Q03: Bill to Establish Department of Americanization (Box 59)
      - Q04: Activities of Americanization Department (Box 59)
      - Q05: Printed Literature for Circulation Among Foreign Born (Box 59)
      - Q05: Connecticut Americanizer (Box 59)
      - Q05.02: Americanization: (Published By Department of Interior, Bureau of Education) (Box 59)
      - Q05.1: Circulars of Americanization Department (Box 59)
      - Q05.11: Un-numbered Circulars of Americanization Department (Box 59)
      - Q05.2: Schedules of Americanization Department (Box 59)
      - Q06: Minutes of Meetings of Committee on Foreign Born Population (Box 59)
      - Q06.1: Meetings of Americanization Committee (Box 59)
      - Q06.2: Americanization Conference, 1918 December 11-12 (Box 59)
      - Q08: Circular Letters of Americanization Department (Box 59)
      - Q11: Lists of Foreign Born in Connecticut (Box 59)
      - Q12: Americanization (General Material) (Box 59)
      - Q13: [Book: Where Garments and Americans are made] (Box 59)
      - Q16: [Pamphlet: Teaching English to Aliens] (Box 59)
      - Q17: [Americanization Textbooks] (Box 59)
      - Q18: [Registration Card for Persons of Foreign Birth] (Box 59)
      - Q99: [Memo re teaching French to Registrants] (Box 59)
      - Q75: Aliens - Naturalization, etc. (Box 59)
      - Q100: German-Americans (Box 59)
      - Q101: Italians (Box 59)
      - Q101.1: Italian day, 1918 May 24 (Box 59)
      - Q102: Poles (Box 59)
      - Q150: Use of English Language in Schools - Elimination of German (Box 59)
      - Q150.1: [Exemptions Concerning Employment of Enemy Aliens in Schools] (Box 59)
      - Q923.03: [Pamphlet: Proclamations, Federal and State Penal Laws and War Regulations (Albany, NY)] (Box 59)
      - Q923.05: [Service Bulletin - Division of Aliens], 1917 June 4 (Box 59)
    - R. Coal (Box 60)
      - R: Coal (Box 60)
      - R: Press Items re Fuel Administration (Box 60)
      - R01: Personnel of Committees (Box 60)
      - R06: [US Fuel Administration and Connecticut Administration Engineering Office - Meeting 12/28/1918 and other Meeting Notices] (Box 60)
      - R08: Circular Letters re fuel Administration, Connecticut T.W. Russell (Box 60)
      - R08.1: US Fuel Administration Circular (Box 60)
      - R13: [Applications for Fuel] (Box 60)
      - R95: [Anthracite Coal] (Box 60)
      - R200: [Press Release; Restrictions on Highway Construction] (Box 60)
      - R100: Soft coal (Box 60)
      - R300: Clerical Assistance and Financial Aid which War Bureaus Should Give Fuel Administrations (Box 60)
      - R600: Wood for Fires (Box 60)
      - R601: Wood Burning in Furnace (Box 60)
      - R621: Cut a Cord (Box 60)
      - R903: New England Coal Committee (Box 60)
    - Ra. Fuel Conservation (Box 60)
      - Ra: Fuel Conservation (Chas. G. Bill, Committee Chairman) (Box 60)
      - Ra051.1: Fuel Conservation Circulars (Box 60)
      - Ra12: Tag Your Shovel Day, 1918 January 30 (Box 60)
      - Ra13: Garfield Closing Orders (General Material About) (Box 60)
      - Ra14: Orders re Closing of Industries - Curtailing of Hours, etc. - Monday closings (Box 60)
      - Ra15: Closing of Saloons (Box 61)
      - Ra16: “Lighless Nights” - Street Lights, etc. (Box 61)
      - Ra21: Coal Savings Posters (Box 61)
      - Ra50: Fuel Conservation inspection - W.R.C. Corson, Administrative Engineer (Box 61)
    - S. Education (Box 61)
      - S: Education - Patriotic (Box 61)
      - S03: [Education Bill S4987] (Box 61)
      - S11: [List of School Committees, Boards of Education - plus Letter re Student’s Enlisted Group] (Box 61)
      - S12: Teachers (Box 61)
      - S15: Evening Schools (Box 61)
      - S15.1: [Poster Urging Foreign Born To Learn English and Write a Letter] (Box 61)
      - S100: Patriotic work by school children (Box 61)
      - S250: Secondary Education (Box 61)
      - S253: [Teaching Courses in War Aims] (Box 61)
      - S378: Colleges & Universities (Box 62)
      - S378: College War Statistics (Box 62)
      - S378.1: Students in the Service of County - Agriculture or other work (Box 62)
      - S400: Employment management courses in colleges (Box 62)
      - S450: Vocational Training (Box 62)
      - S450.05: Suggested Trades for Disabled Men (Box 62)
    - T. Women’s Activities (Box 62)
      - T01: Committee on Women’s Activities - Reorganization 1918 (Box 62)
      - T01: Committee on Women’s Activities - Personnel and Organization (Box 62)
      - T01: Committee on Women’s Activities - Organization (Box 62)
      - T01.1: Organization Committee (of Women’s Committee) (Box 62)
      - T02: [Nominations For Subcommittees on women’s Activities] (Box 62)
      - T04: Activities of Women’s Committee (Box 62)
      - T06: Minutes of Meetings (Women’s Committee) (Box 62)
      - T06.1: Meeting of Women War Workers, 1917 December 6 (Box 62)
      - T08: Circular Letters of Women’s Committee (Box 62)
      - T12: “Women and War Work” (Box 63)
      - T35: Publicity Department (Box 63)
      - T21: [Posters: “Women, Your Country Needs You” and “The Ten Commandments of Womanhood’] (Box 63)
      - T35.3: [Press release re Victory Conferences Sponsored by Committee on Women’s Activities] (Box 63)
      - T65: Red Cross Department of Women’s Committee (Box 63)
      - T75: Italian Women’s Committee (Box 63)
      - T115: Registration of women (Box 63)
      - T150: Speaking by women (Box 63)
      - T320: Woman suffrage (Box 63)
      - T350: Minute women (Box 63)
      - T370: Child welfare (Box 63)
      - T370.01: [Children Year Poster] (Box 63)
      - T371: [Back to school drive] (Box 63)
      - T372: [Feeble minded children] (Box 63)
      - T390: Girl’s Conference, July 10, 1918 (Box 63)
      - T500: [Circular re Future of State Divisions] (Box 63)
      - T902: Council of National Defense, Woman’s Committee (Box 63)
    - V. War Savings (Box 63)
      - V: War Savings - Press Notices, Pamphlets (Box 63)
      - V: Letter to Mayor re Purchase of Stamps (Box 64)
      - V: War Savings Miscellany (Box 64)
      - V01: War Savings Committee Town Chairmen, Committees, etc. (Box 64)
      - V06.1: Vanderlip Meeting, 1917 December 5 (Box 64)
      - V08: War Savings - Circular Letters, Application Blanks, etc. (list of Posters and folders) (Box 64)
      - V12: Prizes for Thrift Campaign (Box 64)
      - V21: Posters (War Savings Stamps) (Box 64)
      - V24: Economy (Box 64)
      - V24: Boston Newspaper’s Refusal to print “Economy Ad” (Box 64)
      - V25: Cost of Social Activities in Schools (Box 64)
      - V26: War Savings Enlistment Campaign, 1918 June (Box 64)
      - V27: War Savings Societies (Connecticut Army of Savers) (Box 64)
      - V28: [Press Release re “Army of Savers”] (Box 64)
      - V150: Speaker’s outlines on War Savings Campaign (Box 64)
    - W. War Chests, Solicitation of Funds, Etc.. (Box 64)
      - W12: Solicitations of War Relief Funds (Box 64)
      - W13: National Investigation Bureau (Box 65)
      - W30: War chests - General Material (Box 65)
      - W30: Mr. Wriston’s Notes, memoranda, etc. (Box 65)
      - W30.01: “No War Chest” Letters (Box 65)
      - W30.01: Other Schemes (Box 65)
      - W30.01: War Chests - Correspondence, 2 folders (Box 65)
      - W30.011: Red Cross Correspondence re War Chest (Box 66)
      - W30.012: War Camp Community Service - Correspondence War Chests (Box 66)
      - W30.013: YMCA Correspondence re War Chests (Box 66)
      - W30.014: War Chests and the Russell Sage Foundation (Box 66)
      - W30.02: Questionnaires re War Chests (A-E) (Box 66)
      - W30.02: Questionnaire F-Z, 2 folders (Box 67)
      - W30.05: War Chests (Mr. Wriston) - Clippings (Box 67)
      - W30.05: War Chests - Press Data (Box 68)
      - W30.05: [Copies of Newspapers: 1) Christian Science Monitor, Boston and 2) The Sun, Springfield, Ohio - articles re war chests], 1918 May (Box 68)
      - W30.06: War chest meeting, 1918 May 7 (Box 68)
      - W31: War Chests - Instructions for Workers, Workers Team Cards (Box 69)
      - W32: Pledge forms, receipt blanks, etc. (Box 69)
      - W33: Reports blanks & envelopes (Box 69)
      - W33: Application Blanks for Appropriations (Box 70)
      - W34: Organization - charts, etc. (Box 70)
      - W35: Constitutions, by-laws, etc. (War Chests) (Box 70)
      - W36: Publicity - (Includes War Chest Songs, etc.) (Box 70)
      - W37: Advertisements, Posters, Photographs, Stickers, 2 folders (Box 71)
      - W38: Window cards (Box 72)
      - W39: Insignia (badges, buttons, etc.) (Box 72)
      - W100: Meriden War Chest (Box 72)
      - W100: New Bedford War Chest (Box 72)
      - W100: [War Chests - Other States, Other Towns] (Box 72)
      - W500: United War Work Campaign Combined Drive - General Material (Box 72)
      - W500.01: United War Work Campaign - Correspondence (Box 73)
      - W500.05: United War Work Campaign - Press Items (Box 73)
      - W501.02: War Camp Community Service - Correspondence re People to Represent them on Combined Drive (Box 73)
      - W502: War Camp Community Service (Box 73)
      - W502.01: Cheney, Austin (Chairman Connecticut War Camp Community Services) - Correspondence (Box 73)
      - W504: Y.W.C.A. in War Fund Drive (Box 73)
      - W505.05: Knights of Columbus Press Data re Combined Drive (Catholic Part in Combined drive) (Box 73)
    - WA. Commercial Relations (Box 73)
      - WA01: Committee on Commercial Relations - Personnel and Organization (Box 73)
      - WA200: Chamber of Commerce Publications (Box 73)
      - WA200: War Trade Board (Box 73)
    - X. Counties (Box 73)
      - X12: Duties of County Chairmen and Secretaries (Box 73)
      - X100: Fairfield County Association (Box 73)
      - X100.02: Suggestions for appointments in Fairfield Co. (Box 73)
      - X302: [Litchfield County Auxiliary Committee] (Box 73)
      - X500.06: New Haven Co. Committee - Minutes of Meetings (Box 73)
      - X800.01: Windham Co. Organization (Box 73)
      - X918: Louisiana (Box 73)
      - X927: [Boone and Dodge Counties, Nebraska] (Box 73)
      - X913.01: Illinois - Organization Chart of State Council of Defense (Box 73)
      - X936.01: Oklahoma State Council of Defense (Box 73)
      - X949.04: Wisconsin State Council of Defense - Report on Activities (Box 73)
    - Y. Towns (Box 73)
      - Y: Community councils (Box 73)
      - Y01: Old Lists of Town Committees (Box 73)
      - Y02: War Bureaus, Fairfield Co. - Suggestions for Appointments (Box 74)
      - Y04: Activities of Town Committees - Suggestions, etc. (Box 74)
      - Y09: Questionnaires - Remarks and Enquiries re (Box 74)
      - Y09: War Record Questionnaires (Filled out) (Box 74)
      - Y11: Local Finance (Box 74)
      - Y12: War Bureaus - General Material About. (Box 74)
      - Y12: War Bureaus - press Notices (Box 75)
      - Y12.01: War Bureaus - Personnel Organization (Box 75)
      - Y15: War Bureau - Emergency organization (Box 75)
      - Y16: Pledges for membership in war bureaus (Box 75)
      - Y17: War bureaus should keep their organization intact for work after end of war. (Box 75)
      - Y25: Field secretaries (Box 75)
      - Y26: Fairfield Co. Field Secretary - Charles F. Greene (Box 75)
      - Y27: Hartford Co. Field Secretary - Richard Wayne (Box 75)
      - Y28: Litchfield Co. Field Secretary - Floyd L. Vanderpoel (Box 75)
      - Y29: Middlesex Co. Field Secretary - Louis S. Smith (Box 75)
      - Y30: New Haven Co. Field Secretary - B. F. English (Box 75)
      - Y31: New London Co. Field Secretary - Allyn F. Brown (Box 75)
      - Y32: Windham and Tolland Co. Field Secretary - Frank J. Brainerd (Box 75)
      - Y128.1: Correspondence with Judge Wheeler of Bridgeport War Bureau and Newspaper Clippings re, Fuel Administrator Siemon (Box 75)
      - Y151: Clinton (Box 75)
      - Y166: Danbury War Bureau (Box 75)
      - Y170.06: [Newspaper Clipping re War Meeting] (Box 75)
      - Y182: East Hartford (Box 75)
      - Y198: Fairfield War Bureau (Box 76)
      - Y200: [Newspaper Clipping - Farmington Valley Herald] (Box 76)
      - Y240.08: Lebanon Patriotic Pilgrimage, September 8, 1918 (Box 76)
      - Y258: Meriden War Bureau (Box 76)
      - Y264: Middletown War Bureau (Box 76)
      - Y276: New Britain War Bureau (Box 76)
      - Y284: New Haven War Bureau (Box 76)
      - Y288: New London War Bureau (Box 76)
      - Y288: New London (Box 76)
      - Y298: Norwich War Bureau (Box 76)
      - Y308.09: Plainville Town Committee - Report (Box 76)
      - Y324: Ridgefield War Bureau (Box 76)
      - Y325: Rockville War Bureau (Box 76)
      - Y344: Simsbury War Bureau (Box 76)
      - Y368.09: Thomaston Town Committee Report (Box 76)
      - Y390: Waterbury War Bureau (Box 76)
      - Y404.09: Wethersfield Town Committee Report (Box 76)
    - Z. General (Box 76)
      - Z01: Bibliography, Publisher’s Announcements, Catalogs, etc. (Box 76)
      - Z01.01: Committee on Public Information - Publications (War Workers of Connecticut) (Box 76)
      - Z02: War Libraries - Literature for Soldiers (Box 76)
      - Z05: [Publications: Atlantic Monthly, Literary Digest, Veterans Journal, and State Guard News] (Box 77)
      - Z05.1: Material re Official Bulletin (Box 77)
      - Z06: War Conferences (Box 77)
      - Z178: Liquor Traffic (Box 77)
      - Z178.1: Prohibition (Liquor) (Box 77)
      - Z200: The War [Publications] (Box 77)
      - Z202: Germany and the War [Publications] (Box 77)
      - Z202: [Germany and the War - Publications] (Box 78)
      - Z208: [Italy Today - Women’s Number] (Box 78)
      - Z209: [Free Poland] (Box 78)
      - Z212: United States in the War (Box 78)
      - Z212.1: America’s War Preparations (Box 78)
      - Z220: The War Causes, Diplomacy, etc. (Box 78)
      - Z222: [Survey of International Relations, Declarations of a State of War] (Box 78)
      - Z223: Peace (Box 78)
      - Z224: Reconstruction Work (Box 78)
      - Z226: [League to Enforce Peace - League of Nations] (Box 78)
    - Historical Records Department (Box 79)
      - Z230: Historical Records Department (Box 79)
      - Z230.03: Circular Letters, Blanks and Forms of Historical Records Department (Box 79)
      - Z230.1: Military Service Record Blanks (Box 79)
      - Z235: History of War to be Written (Box 79)
      - Z235.1: Pictorial History of the War - Appointment of J. Fred Donne to take charge of work in Connecticut (Box 79)
      - Z235.1: Photographs, Maps, etc. Desired by the War Department (Box 79)
      - Z290: Religious War Work (Box 79)
      - Z290.05: [Bulletin - Salve Regina] (Box 79)
      - Z310: [War Record - America and Connecticut] (Box 79)
      - Z320: [American Interest in Popular Government Aboard] (Box 79)
      - Z324.3: Voting by Soldiers Absent from State (Box 79)
      - Z326: Negroes (Box 79)
      - Z328: Congressional Director (Box 79)
      - Z336.24: Income Tax (Box 79)
      - Z336.25: Transportation Tax (Box 79)
      - Z338.7: [Corporate Laws of Connecticut] (Box 79)
      - Z341.2: Prisioners of War (Box 79)
      - Z351.2: Civil Service (Box 79)
      - Z360.4: Offers of property, buildings, etc. for Government use (Box 79)
      - Z361: Sale of Government Supplies which may be purchased for State Institutions (Box 79)
      - Z364: Juvenile Delinquency (Box 79)
      - Z368.2: Insurance, Life (Box 79)